<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1" xmlns:tts="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1#styling" xml:lang="en">
		<body>
      <div xml:lang="en">
         <p begin="00:00:31.26" end="00:00:34.70">It is said that the drum represents the heartbeat of a nation.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:34.70" end="00:00:37.70">In aboriginal cultures, drums are sacred.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:37.70" end="00:00:40.33">Things like that are important for you to know if you are</p>
         <p begin="00:00:40.33" end="00:00:43.80">a Government of Canada employee who will be working with First Nations.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:43.80" end="00:00:47.26">To help introduce you to aboriginal culture, we would also like to tell you</p>
         <p begin="00:00:47.26" end="00:00:49.40">about the Seven Grandfather Teachings.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:49.40" end="00:00:52.76">They are teachings that are often described as embodying the core values</p>
         <p begin="00:00:52.76" end="00:00:54.20">of aboriginal philosophy.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:59.90" end="00:00:63.30">In the Native culture, we say that Mother Earth was created</p>
         <p begin="00:00:63.30" end="00:00:67.66">on the back of a Turtle - Miskwaadesii.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:67.66" end="00:00:72.00">The Turtle represents truth because it is one of the oldest animals on our planet,</p>
         <p begin="00:00:72.00" end="00:00:74.86">and it is said to have witnessed Creation.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:74.86" end="00:00:79.33">The laws of time and life are recorded on the back of a Turtle.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:79.33" end="00:00:85.86">The Turtle is grounded, methodical, careful, and attentive to details.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:85.86" end="00:00:89.10">They are important qualities for those who speak the truth.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:90.03" end="00:00:92.46">The Turtle leads us on the path to truth.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:92.46" end="00:00:96.26">In working for the public, this is a key fundamental value.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:96.26" end="00:00:100.20">Truth inspires us to provide our services in an authentic,</p>
         <p begin="00:00:100.20" end="00:00:103.13">non-partisan and impartial way.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:103.13" end="00:00:106.56">Like the Turtle&apos;s back, on which the cycle of life is inscribed,</p>
         <p begin="00:00:106.56" end="00:00:110.16">these democratic values are inscribed in all of our decisions and actions.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:110.16" end="00:00:114.56">By moving slowly, but surely, the Turtle also reminds us that the journey</p>
         <p begin="00:00:114.56" end="00:00:116.96">is just as important as the destination.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:123.46" end="00:00:128.36">The Buffalo - Bashkode-Bizhiki - represents respect</p>
         <p begin="00:00:128.36" end="00:00:131.03">because for as long as we have been here,</p>
         <p begin="00:00:131.03" end="00:00:135.60">the Buffalo has sustained our lifes through clothing, food and shelter.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:135.60" end="00:00:139.86">The Buffalo is a tool of life to live harmoniously with a sense of balance.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:141.33" end="00:00:144.93">The Buffalo shows us the importance of respecting ourselves and others.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:144.93" end="00:00:149.93">By treating our colleagues as we want them to treat us, with respect and dignity,</p>
         <p begin="00:00:149.93" end="00:00:152.76">we take in consideration their values and ideas</p>
         <p begin="00:00:152.76" end="00:00:155.40">and, in doing so, enhance our own.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:155.40" end="00:00:157.83">Like the Buffalo, the organization can represent</p>
         <p begin="00:00:157.83" end="00:00:161.23">this wealth of resources it provides to us.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:161.23" end="00:00:165.30">In this way, the organization pushes us to maintain respect</p>
         <p begin="00:00:165.30" end="00:00:167.80">toward one another in order to work in harmony.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:173.73" end="00:00:179.70">The Sabe - Kitchi-Sabe - is a mythical giant who is a symbol of honesty.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:179.70" end="00:00:183.10">The Sabe represents honesty because it is believed that the Sabe</p>
         <p begin="00:00:183.10" end="00:00:188.10">used to walk among humans to remind us to remain true to our nature.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:188.10" end="00:00:192.56">The Sabe keeps us aware of being ourselves, and not someone we are not.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:193.16" end="00:00:198.00">The Sabe evokes the principle of honesty, which is so essential in our work.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:198.00" end="00:00:202.00">By being honest and staying true to ourselves and our professional values,</p>
         <p begin="00:00:202.00" end="00:00:205.66">we can avoid any kind of conflict of interest and maintain the trust</p>
         <p begin="00:00:205.66" end="00:00:207.90">of our colleagues and the public.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:207.90" end="00:00:211.56">Being honourable in all of our actions allows us to maintain a healthy</p>
         <p begin="00:00:211.56" end="00:00:213.70">and thriving work environment.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:213.70" end="00:00:217.56">The Sabe is there to remind us to be ourselves and to remain honourable.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:223.66" end="00:00:229.33">The Wolf - Ma&apos;iingan - represents humility because of its giving nature</p>
         <p begin="00:00:229.33" end="00:00:233.50">and devotion to protecting and working for the good of the Wolf family</p>
         <p begin="00:00:233.50" end="00:00:235.60">and the welfare of the pack.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:235.83" end="00:00:238.33">At work, our pack is our team.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:238.33" end="00:00:242.80">By pooling all of our knowledge in the interest of the team as a whole</p>
         <p begin="00:00:242.80" end="00:00:248.23">rather than only for ourselves, we are striving for the excellence of the community</p>
         <p begin="00:00:248.23" end="00:00:250.56">and, as a result, the entire organization.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:250.56" end="00:00:253.80">The Wolf has a protective instinct for its entire pack.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:253.80" end="00:00:257.70">And, like him, we work as part of the group, for the benefit of the group.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:264.23" end="00:00:270.40">The Beaver - Amik - has impressive teeth and has the knowledge of how to build.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:270.40" end="00:00:275.50">If he doesn&apos;t use his gift, his teeth will grow until they will hinder him.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:275.50" end="00:00:279.70">That&apos;s why the Beaver uses his gift wisely to have a positive impact</p>
         <p begin="00:00:279.70" end="00:00:284.13">on its environment and create a more sustainable world.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:284.13" end="00:00:287.23">The Beaver&apos;s wisdom also means knowing what our limits are,</p>
         <p begin="00:00:287.23" end="00:00:290.33">with respect to our body and the life around us.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:291.73" end="00:00:294.26">The Beaver always acts thoughtfully.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:294.26" end="00:00:299.03">He takes full advantage of his resources to make sure they do not go to waste.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:299.03" end="00:00:303.96">At work, the Beaver reminds us how important it is to efficiently use the funds,</p>
         <p begin="00:00:303.96" end="00:00:307.86">property and resources for which we are responsible.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:307.86" end="00:00:312.03">Knowing how to use what we are given to manage and to act with discretion</p>
         <p begin="00:00:312.03" end="00:00:314.40">are wise lessons the Beaver can teach us.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:320.60" end="00:00:326.40">The Bear - Makwa - has strength and natural ability to overcome challenges.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:326.40" end="00:00:331.23">A mother bear will stand against a much larger, stronger male bear</p>
         <p begin="00:00:331.23" end="00:00:333.96">or other threat to protect her cubs.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:333.96" end="00:00:338.76">It&apos;s believed that the Bear calls us to awaken the potential within ourselves</p>
         <p begin="00:00:338.76" end="00:00:341.56">and to stand up for what we believe in.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:342.40" end="00:00:345.26">The Bear teaches us that we can draw from our strengths</p>
         <p begin="00:00:345.26" end="00:00:348.66">to overcome difficult situations we might face at work.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:348.66" end="00:00:353.23">For example, when we are confronted with times of distress as a result of issues</p>
         <p begin="00:00:353.23" end="00:00:357.36">related to harassment or discrimination, the Bear reminds us</p>
         <p begin="00:00:357.36" end="00:00:362.20">of our ability to turn things around by acting with courage and determination.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:367.50" end="00:00:375.83">The Eagle - Migizi - represents love because of its unique relationship with the Creator.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:375.83" end="00:00:379.83">Only the Eagle has the ability and strength to fly higher in the sky than</p>
         <p begin="00:00:379.83" end="00:00:386.60">any other animal, therefore placing it closer to the Creator than all others.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:386.60" end="00:00:390.13">Aboriginal people hold the Eagle feather close to their heart</p>
         <p begin="00:00:390.13" end="00:00:393.70">and consider receiving an Eagle feather to be the greatest gift.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:395.16" end="00:00:400.06">The Eagle reminds us how vital it is to have a visionary approach to our work</p>
         <p begin="00:00:400.06" end="00:00:402.33">and to do it wholeheartedly.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:402.33" end="00:00:405.56">Like the Eagle, when we soar high above,</p>
         <p begin="00:00:405.56" end="00:00:408.26">we get an overview of all our accomplishments.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:408.26" end="00:00:413.30">We get a better understanding of the situation, of ourselves and others</p>
         <p begin="00:00:413.30" end="00:00:415.13">through a broader spectrum.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:415.13" end="00:00:420.53">The Eagle teaches us to act with compassion, vision and acceptance.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:420.53" end="00:00:423.96">And this represents the core values that guide our work.</p>
         <p begin="00:00:423.96" end="00:00:427.03">Understanding the spiritual meaning of these Sacred Teachings,</p>
         <p begin="00:00:427.03" end="00:00:430.80">and how they can guide us, even at work, could help us avoid falling</p>
         <p begin="00:00:430.80" end="00:00:434.43">into a trap of assumptions and generalizations.</p>
    </div>
  </body>
</tt>
